<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Dakotah Peña</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Dakotah Peña</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</managingEditor><webMaster>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</webMaster><copyright>© Dakotah Peña</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 09:23:10 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dakotahpena.studio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Keep Track of Where You Use SMS 2FA</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/posts/track-sms-2fa-with-1password/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 20:48:55 -0700</pubDate><author>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</author><guid>https://dakotahpena.studio/posts/track-sms-2fa-with-1password/</guid><description>If I can make a blanket recommendation, you should be using two-factor authentication for any website or online service that provides it. No matter what that second factor is, be it SMS, one-time passcode, or security key, it decreases the likelihood of your credentials being compromised.
Unfortunately, the majority of services only provide two-factor authentication (2FA) using the SMS method by texting you the temporary code. By having your phone number be one of the critical pieces to get access to parts of your digital life, changing your phone number becomes a terrifying prospect.</description></item><item><title>Give Your Short Term Memory A Break</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/posts/give-short-term-memory-break/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 06:19:10 -0700</pubDate><author>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</author><guid>https://dakotahpena.studio/posts/give-short-term-memory-break/</guid><description>I would wager that taking a shower and brushing your teeth are not something you think about. They are autonomous and there is no chance that you would forget to do them.
If you listed the things you do each day that are recurring tasks but aren&amp;rsquo;t autonomous, you would be surprised how many things you have to remember. Unlike taking a shower, the same can&amp;rsquo;t be said for taking out the trash.</description></item><item><title>Make Less Data: Self-Host Miniflux Feed Reader</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/posts/self-host-miniflux-docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 19:16:46 -0700</pubDate><author>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</author><guid>https://dakotahpena.studio/posts/self-host-miniflux-docker/</guid><description>This is the first in a series about self-hosted services that you can run yourself in order for you to be less of a product of other companies. This means you will be creating less marketable data for these companies and likely saving money in the process.
The shutdown of Google Reader years ago sent ripples across the internet as there was now room for competition in the form of small, paid feed reading services like Feedbin.</description></item><item><title>Human Fund Card</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/work/human-fund-card/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 06:55:14 -0800</pubDate><author>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</author><guid>https://dakotahpena.studio/work/human-fund-card/</guid><description>A donation has been made in your name to The Human Fund.
This is my interpretation of the infamous Human Fund Charity from a Seinfeld episode. Give out this card for Christmas when you are too cheap to buy anyone gifts à la George Costanza.</description></item><item><title>Everyday Carry</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/essays/everyday-carry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 21:44:36 -0700</pubDate><author>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</author><guid>https://dakotahpena.studio/essays/everyday-carry/</guid><description>I like to think of the EDC (everyday carry) concept as prepping light. It’s the first small step towards being prepared for different situations.
There are endless forums for seeing people’s kit but this page aims to give some context to the decision making behind the items rather than just a consumerist show off. My kit is in a constant state of flux the page will be updated as changes are made.</description></item><item><title>Attribution</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/attribution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 21:04:41 -0700</pubDate><author>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</author><guid>https://dakotahpena.studio/attribution/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Personal Calling Card</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/work/personal-calling-card/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 18:20:47 -0700</pubDate><author>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</author><guid>https://dakotahpena.studio/work/personal-calling-card/</guid><description>Grid of characters with name highlighted in red.
3.5&amp;quot; x 2&amp;quot; Matte stock</description></item><item><title>First Aid Kit</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/work/first-aid-kit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 18:09:41 -0700</pubDate><author>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</author><guid>https://dakotahpena.studio/work/first-aid-kit/</guid><description>50 caliber ammo canister converted into first aid kit. Coated auto body paint.</description></item><item><title>Coeur d'Alene Tech Group Website</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/work/cda-tech-website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 07:43:54 -0700</pubDate><author>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</author><guid>https://dakotahpena.studio/work/cda-tech-website/</guid><description>Coeur d&amp;rsquo;Alene Tech Group Website</description></item><item><title>Fixie Bike</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/work/bike/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 07:43:54 -0700</pubDate><author>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</author><guid>https://dakotahpena.studio/work/bike/</guid><description>Setting out to design a bike from scratch, I started with a raw steel frame. Designed piece-by-piece. One gear, one brake.
Parts:
Mission Bicycles frame Velo Orange handle bar Brooks B-17 saddle Bianchi stem Shimano Ultegra brake Weimann wheels Veloflex Record tyres MKS pedals Sugino crankset</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 09:44:51 +0200</pubDate><author>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</author><guid>https://dakotahpena.studio/about/</guid><description>About I&amp;rsquo;m Dakotah, a maker based in Coeur d&amp;rsquo;Alene, Idaho. Professionally, I am a full-stack web developer specializing in Ruby on Rails, Go, and Angular. On a personal level, I like to design things.
Random Facts I&amp;rsquo;m a milk tea enthusiast Studied fashion design and tailoring. Designed and sewed a small collection. I think far too much about the things I carry around with me. Leadership Coeur d&amp;rsquo;Alene Tech Group Organizer of local technology meetup to unite the disparate technology community.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/contact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 09:44:51 +0200</pubDate><author>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</author><guid>https://dakotahpena.studio/contact/</guid><description> Contact me If you have a question or comment, feel free to use the form below or email hey@dakotahpena.studio Name Email Your Message</description></item><item><title>FaceTime Audio Versus Voice Cost Analysis</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/posts/facetime-audio-cost-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 17:44:14 -0800</pubDate><author>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</author><guid>https://dakotahpena.studio/posts/facetime-audio-cost-analysis/</guid><description>Years ago many pundits and technophiles lamented the lack of a data-only cellular carrier. Because the carriers could price different modes of communication, be it voice, data, SMS, differently it means they could adjust their profits over time as usage of these different channels shifted so they could stay ahead of any curve.
The argument for a data-only provider is that all communication can be transmitted over data and we can have one single method of communicating on a mobile phone and thereby turning providers into dumb pipes like a cable internet connection.</description></item><item><title>Always Carry Perfect Change</title><link>https://dakotahpena.studio/essays/perfect-change/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>hey@dakotahpena.studio (Dakotah)</author><guid>https://dakotahpena.studio/essays/perfect-change/</guid><description>People pay with cash less and less these days, particularly with change. Transactions under twenty dollars can be worth paying in cash, to me. The finality of the transaction is refreshing. Additionally, small local businesses prefer cash because they don't have to absorb the processing fee.
I often just hand over the most efficient bank note and put the change in a container for a future CoinStar trip.</description></item></channel></rss>